NWLB Non-Ferrous Metals Commission Records 5314
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
NWLB Non-Ferrous Metals Commission Records
1943
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. National War Labor Board (NWLB)
5314
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Dispute cases referred to the Non-ferrous Metals Commission of the National War Labor Board.
5596297
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 19, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Non-Ferrous Metals Commission was one of several tripartite industry commissions set up by the National War Labor Board to deal with particular industries on a national rather than a regional basis. The Board felt that technical, economic, and other factors called for industry-wide treatment in these cases. The Commission made final decisions subject only to appeal to the National Board.
Scope and Contents
Consists primarily of transcripts of hearings, briefs, and answers of unions and employers, and reports and recommendations of Mediation Panels regarding dispute settlement cases brought before the Non-Ferrous Metals Commissions of the US National War Labor Board (1943-1945).
A-I companies: American Smelting and Refining Company vs. International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers (IUMMSW) and United Steel Workers of America (1944-1945) on issues of wages, hours of work, sick leave, shift differential, collective agreement, holiday, pension, military leave, benefits, position classification, health insurance, grievance procedure, arbitration, vacation, and management rights; Anaconda Copper Mining Company vs. IUMMSW, Metal Trades Council of the A.F. of L. and the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers severance pay, hours of work, grievance procedure, sick pay, arbitration, shift differential, promotion, military leave, management rights, union security, and health insurance; Empire Zinc Company vs. IUMMSW (1944) on issues of severance pay, checkoff, position classification, hours of work, vacation, wages, portal to portal pay, union security, sick leave, and military leave; and Inspirational Consolidated Copper Company vs. Metal Trades Department of the A.F. of L., Miami Miners' Union, and IUMMSW (1945) on issues of union security, collective agreement, wages, closed shop, vacation, shift differential, sick leave, severance pay, and position classification.
Companies K-R: Kennecott Copper Corporation vs. Chino Metal Trades Council of Grant County, N.M., and Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, International Association of Machinists, IUMMSW, International Union of Operating Engineers, and White Plains Metal Trades Council (1943-1945) on issues of position classification, collective agreement, work assignment, seniority, checkoff, mainenance of membership, sick leave, promotion, commuting, vacation, shift differential, union shop, union security, wages, portal to portal pay, and promotion; Phelps Dodge Refining Corporation vs. IUMMSW (1943) on issues of grievance procedure, wage incentive, defense production, position classification, union security, absenteeism, sick pay, shift differential, vacation, wages, and checkoff; and Resurrection Mining Company vs. IUMMSW (1944-1945) on issues of retroactive pay, severance pay, shift differential, maintenance of membership, checkoff, wages, and sick leave.
U-V Companies: US Potash Company of America vs. International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers (IUMMSW), International Association of Machinists and Potash Workers Union (1944-1945) on issues of promotion, vacation, wage adjustment, wages, meal period, contracting out, position classification, shift differential, overtime, and hours of work; Utah Copper Company (Kennecott Corporation) vs. Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, International Association of Operating Engineers, and IUMMSW (1943-1945) on issues of promotion, insurance, military leave, severance pay, meal period, shift differential, wage adjustment, portal to portal pay, wages, sick leave, vacation, arbitration, commuting, union shop and hours of work; Utah Copper Mines (Utah Block) vs. IUMMSW (1944) on issues of wages, seniority, vacations, sick pay, health insurance, recognition, union security, and arbitration; and Vanadium Corporation of America vs. IUMMSW, United Mine Workers of America, and International Union of Operating Engineers (1943-1944) on issues of military leave, sick leave, commuting, vacation, portal to portal pay, safety, shift differential, maintenance of membership, wages, union security, seniority, union shop, checkoff, and premium pay.
Additional documents generated by the Non-Ferrous Metals Commission include directive orders; bulletins; handbook of dispute settlement procedures; minutes; summary of significant Commission actions; lists of dispute settlement cases brought before the Commission; correspondence of Commission members, and representatives of unions and employers regarding hearings and case disposition; and memoranda concerning wages, absenteeism, labor shortages, and production (1943-1945).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Metal-workers -- United States.; Collective bargaining -- Metal-workers -- United States.; Metal-workers -- Labor unions -- United States.; United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945)
5596297
- Utah Cooper Company Bingham, Utah 111-10911-D (22-D-156), 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Utah Copper Co. Magna and Arthur, Utah 111-9529-D(22-D-142), 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Utah Copper Co. July Session 4 Cases, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Utah Copper Company 111-6064-D(22-D-119) 111-6065-D(22-D-120), 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Utah Copper Co., 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1944 Utah Block of Cases (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Utah Copper Company Arthur, Utah 111-12179-D 22-D-164, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Vanadium Corporation of America 22-D-71 NWLB 111-2022-D (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Vanadium Corp. of America Monticello, Utah NWLB 22-D-81 111-4116-D, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Golden Cycle Corp. 111-17257-D (22-D-209), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Utah Copper Company 107-108 119-120, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Kennecott Copper Company, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Potash Company of America 111-17736-D 22-D-216, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- New Mexico Bloc (6) 22-D-159; 185; 188; 189; 190; 173, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Peru Mining Company Hanover, N.M. 22-D-37 NWLB 111-276-D, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Peru Mining Company & N.M. Cons. Mining Co. 22-D-109 111-570-D, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Mr. O'Brien (Phelps Dodge) Laurel Hill +, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Phelps Dodge Corp. Morenci & Tyrone, N.M., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Phelps Dodge Corp. 111-5671-D 22-D-113, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Resurrection Mining Company Leadville, Colorado Case No. NWLB 111-13981-D (22-D-186), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- St. Joseph Lead Company 22-D-30 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Shattuck Denn Mining Corp. NWLB 2642-CS-D, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Phelps Dodge Corporation Bisbee, Arizona 22-D-157, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Philipsburg, Montana Ming and Trucking Companies, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Potash Co. Of America U.S. Potash Co., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Resurrection Mining Co. Leadville, Colorado 22-D-131, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Mr. Jenson, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Howe Sound Mining Company Chelan Div. of Holden, Wa., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Howe Sound Company Holden, Washington, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Inspiration Consolidated Copper Company 22-D-35 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Inspiration Cons. Copper Company 22-D-43 (IUMM&SW) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Inspiration Consolidated Copper Company International Smelting and Refining Company Inspiration, Arizona, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- International Smelting & Refining Company 22-D-36 (A.F.L.) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Kalunite Inc. Salt Lake City, Utah 111-9102-D, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Kennecott Copper Corp. 22-D-13 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Kennecott Copper Corporation Chino Division, Hurley, N.M. NWLB Case 11-112-C, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Kennecott Copper Corp. Chino Mines Div., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Kennecott Copper Corp. NWLB 111-1029-D, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Kennecott Copper Corp. Santa Rita Hurley, N.M. NWLB 111-2672-D, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Kennecott Copper Corp. Chino Mines Div., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Kennecott Copper Co. 111-5804-D, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Kennecott Copper Corp. McGill, Nev. 111-6048-D, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Kennecott Copper Corp. Nevada Mine Division & AFL 22-D-135, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Kennecott Copper Corporation Ruth and McGill, Nevada Case No. NWLB 111-13703-D, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Keystone Copper Company Copperopolis, California Case No. NWLB 111-14039-HO (22-D-187), 1945 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Kennecott Copper Corporation Nevada Mines Division NWLB 111-14129-D (22-D-191), 1945 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Kennecott Copper Corp. (Nevada Mines Div.) McGill, Nevada Case No. NWLB, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Kennecott Copper Corp. (Nevada Mines Div. McGill, Nevada Case No. NWLB 111-16705-JB, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Morris P. Kirk & Son, Inc. Los Angeles, California Case No. NWLB 111-15482-D, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Klies Mining Company Neihart, Montana NWLB 111-656-D, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Klies Mining Company Neihart, Montana NWLB 111-656-D, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Miami Copper Co. Miami, Arizona 111-13177-D, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Mammoth St. Anthony Ltd. NWLB 111-2041-D, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Manuel of Decisions (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Meyerhoff Panel Cases, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous - July 1943 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Miscellaneous Aug. 1943 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Miscellaneous Sept. 1943 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Miscellaneous Nov. 1943 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous Dec. 1943 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Miscellaneous Jan. 1944 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Miscellaneous - March 1944 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Miscellaneous May 1944 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Miscellaneous June 1944 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Miscellaneous July 1944 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Miscellaneous Sept. 1944 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Miscellaneous Nov. 1944 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Miscellaneous Jan. 1945 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Miscellaneous February-March 1946 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Miscellaneous April 1945 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Miscellaneous Folder: May 1945 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Morris P. Kirk and Son, Inc., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- U.S. Smelting, Refining & Mining. Co., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Miami Copper Company, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Mr. O'Brien (Michigan), 1943 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Miami Copper Co. Int'l Smelting & Ref. Co. Inspiration Cons. Copper Co., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Eagle-Picher Mining and Smelting company Tucson, Arizona NWLB 111-14489-D, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Electro Metallurgical Company Spokane, Washington, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- The Empire Zinc Company 111-4156-D, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- The Empire Zinc Company Hanover, N.M. 111-4994-D, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Empire Zinc Company Gilman, Colorado, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Garfield Vanadium Mine NWLB 111-1068-D, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- General Chemical Company NWLB 111-2551-D, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- The Golden Cycle Corporation Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Banner Mining Company Lordsburg, N.M. 111-12485-D, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Black Hawk Cons. Mimes Co. Hanover, N.M., 1944 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Bunker Hill and Sullivan Mining and Concentrating Co., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Callahan Zinc-Lead Co. Nogales, Ariz. 22-D-134, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Carlota Copper Company Miami, Arizona NWLB 111-1733-D, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Castle Dome Copper Co. Inc. 22-D-123, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Climax Molybdenum Co. Climax, Colorado 111-12487-D, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Castle Dome Copper Company, Inc. Miami, Arizona, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Colo. Floorspar Corp. Salida, Colorado 111-12333-D, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Consolidated Coppermines Corp., 1943 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Anaconda Copper Mining Co. Flathead Mine, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Anaconda Copper Mining Co. 111-12601-D, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Anaconda Copper Mining Co., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Anaconda Copper Mining Co. 111-12837-D, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Anaconda Coper Mining Co. East Helena, Montana, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Anaconda Copper Mining Company Conda, Idaho, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Anaconda copper Co. East Helena, Mont., 1944 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Anaconda Copper Mining. Co. Anaconda & Great Falls, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Anaconda Copper Mining Company, Butte, Anaconda and Great Falls 111-4995-D, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Amer. Smelting & Ref. Co. Selby, California 22-D-155, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Amer. Smelting & Ref. Co. Leadville, Colorado, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- American Smelting & refining Co. East Helena, Montana 22-D-177, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- American Smelting & Refining Company (Globe Plant) Denver, Colorado, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Anaconda Copper Mining Company (Benbow, Mouart & Gish Mines), 1943 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Mine Wage Scales in the Tri-State (Oklahoma-Kansas-Missouri) District, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- United States Vanadium Corp. (Salt Lake City), 1943 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- U.S. Vanadium Corp., 1943 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- U.S. Vanadium Corp., 1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- U.S. Vanadoum Corp., 1943 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- U.S. Vanadium Corp. Uravan, Colorado, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- U.S. Vanadium Corp. Red Lodge, Mont., 1943 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Utah Companies (10) folder #3, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Vanadium Corp. of America Naturita, Colorado, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Utah Companies (10) Folder 2, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- 1944 Utah Block of Cases (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Vanadium Corporation of America Natarita, Colorado Case No. NWLB 111-13178-D (22-D-181), 1945 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Vanadium Corp. of America Naturia, Colorado, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Verbatim Transcript National War Labor Board 13 Metal Mining Company, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Verbatim Transcript National War Labor Board Salt Lake Mining Company, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Mine Wage Scales in the Tri-State (Oklahoma - Kansas - Missouri) District, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Case No. 22-D-85 to 22-D-94, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- American Smelting & Refining Company, and International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, CIO, Locals Nos. 365, 393, 431, 488 and 557, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Verbatim Transcript National War Labor Board (Hearing Before Board), 1942 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- National War Labor Board Misc., 1942-1945 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Verbatim Transcript NWLB American Smelting and Refining Company, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- NWLB; Miners and Smelters, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- NWLB Misc., 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Progressive Metalworker, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- 'Industrial Worker' Newspaper, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Misc. Papers Folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Misc. Papers Folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Misc. Papers Folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- National War Labor Board, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Index and Summary of Dispute Cases Referred to the Nonferrous Metals Commission, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- American Smelting and Refining Co. San Francisco 111-4358-D, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- American Smelting and Refining Co. Ark. Valley 111-4445-HO, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- American Smelting and Refining Co. Tacoma Washington 111-4823-D, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- American Smelting and Refining Company Los Angeles, California 111-4850-D, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- American Smelting and Refining Company 111-5403-D, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Amer. Smelting and Refining Co. Magdalena Unit, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Amer. Smelting and Refining globe Plan 111-5444-D, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Amer. Smelting & Ref. Co. Ground Hog - Hanover 22-D-126, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Amer. Smelting and Refining Co. Patagonia, Arizona 22-D-133, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Amer. Smelting and Refining Co. Tacoma Washington 22-D-152, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- American Smelting and Refining Co. 22-D-165, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- American Smelting and Refining Company (Tacoma, Washington) NWLB 22-D-28, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Amer. Smelting and Refining Co. Vanadium, N.M. 111-613-D, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- American Smelting and Refining Company, Globe Plant NWLB-237-D (Box 6, Folder 16)
- American Smelting and Refining Company, Globe Plant, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Amer. Smelting and Refining Co. East Helena, Mont. NWLB 111-3781-D, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Miami Copper Company Miami, Arizona NWLB 111-15038-D, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- NWLB, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Mr. O'Brien (Miscellaneous), 1943 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Mr. O'Brien (AS&R), East Alton, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Shattick Denn Mining Corporation Bisbee, Arizona, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Shattuck-Denn Mining Corp. Bisbee Ariz. NWLB, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- U.S. Vanadium Corp. Rifle Colorado, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- U.S. Smelting, Refining and Mining Co. Midvale, Utah, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- U.S. Smelting, Refining and Mining. Co. Midvale, Utah Case No. 111-15788-D, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- United States Vanadium Corporation Uravan, Colorado Case No. 111-14173-D, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Utah Cases, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Shattuck Denn Mining Corp. NWLB 111-763-D, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- U.S. Smelting, Refining and Mining Co. Lark Utah 22-D-129, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- U.S. Smelting, Refining and Mining Co. 22-D-118, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Mr. O'Brien (Tri-State Cases), 1943 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- United States Smelting, Refining and Mining Co. NWLB 111-1456-D, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Tintic Standard Mining Company Dividend, Utah, and the North Lily Mining Company Bureka, Utah, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Shenandoah Dives Mining Co. NWLB 111-857-D, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Utah Companies (10) Folder 2, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Mines Division of Copper Queen Branch of Phelps Dodge Corporation Biebee, Arizona -and- International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, Local No. 551 Bisbee, Arizona, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Nonferrous Metals Commission of the NWLB, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Utah Companies (10) Folder #3, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- 22-D-142, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 19)